Yash Kadaru Engineer | Designer

+1 647-782-3531 hello@yashkadaru.com yashkadaru.com

Highlights

8+ years experience building software that embodies good design, clear purpose, and skillful engineering. I'm eager and quick to learn, creative in my work, and a strong communicator and mentor.

Technical Tools Javascript (Typescript, React, Redux, Angular, Vue.js, Node.js, Express, Socket.io), C#/.NET Framework/.NET Core, CSS/LESS/Sass, PostCSS/Tailwind, Python (data extraction and analytics only), PHP, Ruby on Rails, Java, Postgres, MongoDB, MySQL, Bundling & Task Runner Tools (Webpack, ESBuild, Vite, Turborepo, Gulp), DevOps Tools (PM2, nodemon, Gitlab CI/CD, Codeship, BuddyCI), Docker, NGINX, XML & Mail (Flowgear, Mailgun, Sendgrid), Payment (Stripe, Braintree), Testing (Jest, Storybook, JUnit, Cypress, Ghost Inspector, Email on Acid), Hosting & Cloud Infrastructure (Firebase & GCP, Vercel, Hookdeck, Netlify, AWS, Heroku, Cloudflare), DX (Postman, Sentry, PostHog), Design (Sketch, Figma, Zeplin)

Freelance and Personal Projects

Pigeon

A simplified, efficient take on the traditional IT Help Desk that I pitched, designed, and developed at my first job (2015) [PHP, SQL, HTML/Sass, JS]

Cahoots Theatre Company

Rebranded, designed, and developed the website for a well-known Toronto theatre company. (2023) [Webflow CMS, Sketch]

Matcha

Pitched a service that uses data science to intelligently match restaurants & suppliers to other similar entities to reduce food waste. Won 3rd place in FinTech challenge at Elevate Tech Fest (2020) [React, Tailwind, Firebase]

Experience

Senior Software Engineer | Swyft

July 2022 - Current

Created our startup's ground-breaking logistics product, "marketplace", in four months. Orchestrated and executed three major projects to build on our initial launch (shipment management, invoices and reports, tracking page revamp), meeting our six-week deadline through meticulous design, scoping, collaboration, and development. Built a new app onboarding system, as well as a new shipment creation flow, in less than a month, while also supporting our current users. Led, supported, and mentored the Product team, resulting in on-time and well-executed delivery for all projects.

Software Developer II & Educator | Konrad Group & BrainStation

May 2018 - May 2022

Developed a Shopify-powered storefront prototype that **won a multi-billion dollar client**. Developed an AEM, Java, Web Tech (HTML, CSS, Javascript), and GraphQL powered **online storefront** for a **major retailer**. Contributed to two Angular projects for the **Royal Bank of Canada**. **Taught two, three-month Web Development Bootcamps** at BrainStation, with an overall **4.7/5 educator rating**. **Developed a CMS** for the entire curriculum, which had not previously existed, and created **original** lesson plans, lectures, workshops, take-home projects, and whiteboard exercises which Educators continue to use today. **Contributed to BrainStation's entire technology portfolio**, building features for various applications such as their flagship LMS - Synapse, Internal CRM and administration dashboard - Cortex, Marketing Site, Annual Digital Skills Survey, and a Gutenberg-enabled WordPress publishing platform. Built these projects leveraging *C#*, .NET, Postgres, React, Redux, Node.js, AWS infrastructure, Webpack, and other technologies.

Software Developer | Ian Martin Group & Fitzii

May 2016 - August 2017

Built automation infrastructure in C#/.NET that were critical in improving efficiency and employee/contractor satisfaction. Independently managed projects from design to implementation, balancing the needs of four different stakeholders. Built a career portal in Angular (careers.ianmartin.com), increasing candidate engagement (84%) compared to their previous WordPress site. Built an automated system that sent out company-funded redemption codes to contractors, allowing them to donate to various charities through the Kiva platform. This new system created a 60% increase in loans and allowed Ian Martin to beat Google in loans per month. Built an automated privacy consent tracking system in React. Leveraged Ruby on Rails to contribute to Fitzii, a digital hiring and application platform powered by data science and psychology.

Junior Developer | McMaster University

November 2014 - May 2016

Pitched and built the 'Pigeon' app to help staff from five sub-departments communicate their IT requests more efficiently. **Helped maintain existing apps** for move-in, move-out, department inventory, and residence tours. **Designed various graphics** that were used in key campus events, such as Welcome Week Info Cards and Move-In Schedules. **Maintained IT infrastructure for five sub-departments.** Managed the streaming content display system in residences. **Pitched and implemented remote monitoring** for this system, which **increased uptime by 25%** and made management easier & more efficient

Education

Software Engineering & Co-op | McMaster University

September 2013 - 2019

Awarded entrance scholarship and bursaries in second and third year for high academic standing. Active participation in intramural sports for four years.

Special Interests

Adjudicated the Canada-Wide Virtual Science Fair for the Technology category - **2021**Attended several Hackathons (Hack the North, YHacks, DeltaHacks, Elevate - 3rd place winner) - **2014, 2015, 2016, 2020**Volunteered for the Deltahacks Management Team and helped start McMaster's first technology club, HackItMac - **2015**